Finding Aid for Interfaith Council of Congregations (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records, 1970-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Interfaith Council of Congregations (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records 1970-2008
Interfaith Council of Congregations (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
3 linear feet
85228 Aa 2
Committee and task force reports, correspondence, pamphlets, and clippings largely concerning the responses of local churches to problems of poverty, hunger, child care, and other social questions.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were the gift of the organization (donor no. 6524 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Inter-faith Coalition of Congregations was formed in 1970 largely in response to demands made to area churches by the Black Economic Development League director Charles Thomas that the churches pay "reparations" to fund self-help programs to alleviate some of the needs of the poor and disadvantaged in Washtenaw County. In 1973, following a merger with the Ypsilanti Inter-Faith Council for Social Action, the name of the organization was changed to the Interfaith Council of Congregations. Some of the early results of the funding provided by the churches were the Green-Glacier Community Center, the Peace Neighborhood Center, the Interfaith Council on Human Needs, and a dental program for poor children. The number of participating churched peaked in the mid to late 1970s, but the organization continued to operate into the 1990s.
The record group includes administrative and organizational files, including minutes of the executive committee, and topical files describing some of the programs funded by the organization. Within the files, the researcher will find reports, memoranda, printed material, and records of the needs task forces set up by the Council. The records date primarily from 1970 to 1981 with some funding files from the 1990s up to 2007/2008.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Church history.; Children--Health and hygiene--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Poverty--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Social problems--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Social service--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies, etc.; Child care--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Interfaith Council of Congregations (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
- Topical files 1970-1981
  - American Red Cross (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Child Care and Development Center (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Community Center (Box 1)
  - Articles of Incorporation 1970 (Box 1)
  - Assembly, minutes 1972-1981 (Box 1)
  - Bethel A.M.E. Church Day Care Center (Box 1)
  - Black Business News (Box 1)
  - Black Economic Development League (Box 1)
  - Boys' Club of Ypsilanti (Box 1)
  - Catholic Social Service (Box 1)
  - Child and Family Service (Box 1)
  - Child care center (Box 1)
  - Church Related Services Task Force (Box 1)
  - Clothing and Welfare Needs Task Force (Box 1)
  - Clothing Coop Committee (Box 1)
  - Coalition for Legislative and Social Action (Box 1)
  - Committee for New Understanding of Justice (Box 1)
  - Community Camp Placement Committee (Box 1)
  - Community Coordinated Child Care (Box 1)
  - Community Day Care and Pre-School Center (Box 1)
  - Community Newspaper Proposal (Box 1)
  - Concentrated Code Enforcement (Box 1)
  - Constitution and Bylaws (Box 1)
  - Cooperative Extension Service (Box 1)
  - Cooperative Services, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (acknowledgements for contributions) December 1970-May 1971 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (miscellaneous) October 1970-February 1981 (Box 1)
  - Council on Alcoholism (Box 1)
  - County Assistance Policy (Box 1)
  - Day Care Centers (Box 1)
  - Drug Task Force (Box 1)
  - Education Committee (Box 1)
  - Education Task Force (Box 1)
  - Equal Justice Council, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Executive Board Minutes undated, 1970-1981, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Finance committee (Box 1)
  - Financial Secretary reports (Box 1)
  - First Presbyterian Church Fund Raising (Box 1)
  - First Presbyterian Church Scholarship Program (Box 1)
  - First United Methodist Church (Box 1)
  - Fish (Box 1)
  - Fund Proposals (Box 1)
  - Fund raising (Box 1)
  - Goals (Box 1)
  - Green-Glacier Community Center (Box 1)
  - Guidelines for liaison representatives (Box 1)
  - Health care (Box 1)
  - Health Task Force (Box 1)
  - House by the Side of the Road (Box 1)
  - Housing (Box 1)
  - Humaneness in Education (Ann Arbor Public Schools) (Box 1)
  - Humaneness in Education (selected schools), 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Huron Valley Girl Scouts (Box 1)
  - Information and Referral Service. Washtenaw County Mental Health Clinic (Box 1)
  - Interfaith Center for Human Needs (Box 1)
  - Interreligious Foundation for Community Organization, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Jessye, Eva (Box 1)
  - Joint Strategy and Action Committee (Box 1)
  - Kidney Foundation of Michigan, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Kiwanis (Box 1)
  - Literacy Council of Washtenaw County (Box 1)
  - Membership lists (Box 1)
  - Michigan Annual Reports (Box 1)
  - Michigan Council of Churches (Box 1)
  - Milan Guest House (Box 1)
  - Model Cities (Box 1)
  - National Committee on the Self-Development of People (Box 1)
  - National Cystic Fibrosis Foundation (Box 1)
  - Needlework Guild (Box 1)
  - Neighborhood Centers Project (Box 1)
  - New Bethel Community Center (Box 1)
  - Newsletter Visions (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Articles (Box 1)
  - Northside Drop-In Center (Box 2)
  - Northside Neighborhood Center (Box 2)
  - Octagon House (Box 2)
  - Organization. Internal (Box 2)
  - Our Own Thing, Inc. (Box 2)
  - Peace Neighborhood Center (Box 2)
  - Permanent Resource Committee (Box 2)
  - Personal Involvement Task Force (Box 2)
  - Pontiac Heights Community Pre-school (Box 2)
  - Priorities Committee (Box 2)
  - Private Agencies Task Force (Box 2)
  - Procedures in gifts, designations, and benevolence 1971 (Box 2)
  - Public Agencies Task Force (Box 2)
  - Public Structures Task Force (Box 2)
  - Publicity (church publications) (Box 2)
  - Publicity (clippings) (Box 2)
  - Publicity materials (Box 2)
  - Racism clippings (Box 2)
  - Saline Area Social Services (Box 2)
  - Salvation Army (Box 2)
  - Second Baptist Day Care Nursery (Box 2)
  - Senior Citizens Guild (Box 2)
  - Southside Action Coalition (Box 2)
  - Students Offering Support (Box 2)
  - Sumpter Clothing Center (Box 2)
  - Sumpter Summer Program (Box 2)
  - Tenth Anniversary (Box 2)
  - Theology Task Force (Box 2)
  - Treasurer's Reports (Box 2)
  - Unemployment (Box 2)
  - United Cerebral Palsy Association (Box 2)
  - Village Adoption (Box 2)
  - Visiting Nurse Association (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw Association for Retarded Children (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw Community Bail Fund (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw County Citizens Committee on Aging (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw County Community Services Agency (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw County Council of Churches (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw County Council of Churches. Department of Social Services (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw County Council of Churches and IFCC Merger Discussions (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw County Juvenile Court Center (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw County League for Planned Parenthood (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw County Office of Economic Opportunity (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw United Fund (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw Youth Services Bureau, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Wee Friends Nursery (Box 2)
  - Welfare Advocacy Program (Box 2)
  - Welfare Background information (Box 2)
  - Welfare Rights Organization (Box 2)
  - Whitmore Lake Neighborhood Center (Box 2)
  - Willow Run Area Medical Clinic (Box 2)
  - Willow Run High School Proposals (Box 2)
  - Women's Craft and Small Business Guild (Box 2)
  - Women's Crisis Center (Box 2)
  - YW-YMCA (Box 2)
  - Ypsilanti Commission on the Aging (Box 2)
  - Ypsilanti Meals on Wheels (Box 2)
- Funding requests
  - Funding cycle 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Funding cycle 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Funding cycle 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Funding cycle 2001-2002 (Box 3)
  - Funding cycle 2003-2004 (Box 3)
  - Funding cycle 2005-2006 (Box 3)
  - Funding cycle 2007-2008 (Box 3)
- Other records
  - Treasurer's file 1999-2005 (Box 3)
  - Agency thank you letters (Box 3)
  - Charitable trust annual reports 1971-1985 (Box 3)
  - Congregation pledge forms (Box 3)
  - By-laws (Box 3)
  - Press releases / publicity (Box 3)
  - Photographs (Box 3)